Sanjana Danait

+1 571-699-9656

sdanait@umd.edu

sanjanadanait.com

Sanjana has 1.5 years of experience in designing innovative and accessible user experiences for various products, ranging from e-commerce to healthcare. She excels at using critical thinking to solve complex problems and balancing user needs with business goals. She has previously also worked in creative fields such as architecture and set design.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Human-Computer Interaction | University of Maryland, College Park

Aug 2022 - May 2024

GPA: 4.0 | Coursework: Fundamentals of HCI, Interaction Design, Information Architecture

Bachelor of Architecture | Academy of Architecture, University of Mumbai

Jul 2015 - Oct 2020

SKILLS

Design: User Experience Design, User Interface Design, Product Design, Visual Design, Design System, Prototyping, Wireframing, Information Architecture, Typography, User Flows, Branding

Research: UX Research, Journey Mapping, Personas, Usability & Accessibility Testing, A/B Testing, Heuristic Evaluation Technical: Figma, Sketch, Miro, Invision, Zeplin, Adobe Creative Suite (Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe InDesign), Microsoft Office, AutoCAD, Sketchup, Revit, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Professional: Effective Communication, Problem-Solving, Critical Thinking, Client Management, Time Management

WORK EXPERIENCE

Product Experience Designer | Mindstix Software Labs, Pune, India Awarded Star Performer - Certificate of Excellence in Jan 2022

Jun 2021 - Jun 2022

Dental Practice Management SaaS platform + Patient Portal I Early stage healthcare start-up, USA

- Independently led the project by conducting user research, creating the information architecture & design system, and designing high fidelity prototypes of 150+ screens; instrumental in the client raising \$2M in seed funding
- Conducted competitive research & analysed 8 products to identify current market gaps, aiding in feature ideation
- Worked on complex domains like claims, billing, scheduling, medical imaging & electronic health records
- Facilitated brainstorming workshops with the clients and a team of 15 designers to design the company logo
- Collaborated with the clients, the product manager, QA engineer, and a team of 12 developers to steer UX reviews E-Commerce & CRM | Health & Wellness Company, North America
- Actively participated in design discussions and contributed to 20+ component families in the global design system
- · Generated 6 customer registration flows for web and mobile platforms to improve consistency and readability

UX Design Intern | Mindstix Software Labs, Pune, India

Mar 2021 - May 2021

Travel Retail Platform Revamp | Fortune 500 Luxury Cosmetics Company, North America

- Created and modified visual designs for over 30 web and mobile screens including dashboards and forms
- Coordinated with the product manager and a team of 5 developers to conduct design review meetings

HCP Digital Engagement Platform I Healthcare start-up, India

Conceptualized visual designs for 12 key mobile screens and created hi-fidelity prototypes for client presentation

Intern Architect | SJK Architects, Mumbai, India

Nov 2018 - May 2019

- Prepared 50+ design and site execution drawings for an administrative & research facility and a hotel project
- · Organized and actively participated in meetings with external consultants, vendors and clients

Assistant Set Designer | Art Direction Department, Film & Television Institute of India, Pune

Apr 2017 - May 2017

- Created a miniature set depicting an absolutely devastated city for a short film 'Ekaant'
- The film won 7 awards, Notable Award: The 66th National Film Award for Art Direction

PROJECTS

Accessibility Inspection | UMD | Course: Fundamentals of HCI | Grade: A+

Nov 2022 - Dec 2022

- Inspected Council of Architecture, India's website through screen readers and automated tools like WAVE
- Identified WCAG 2.1 violations based on these inspections and suggested top 3 accessibility improvements

System Analysis | UMD | Course: Information Architecture | Grade: A

Oct 2022 - Dec 2022

- Conducted user research and analysed data architecture to identify key problem areas in MDOT MVA's website
- Proposed a new navigation structure, user journey maps and wireframes to address the identified issues

VRearth - Speculative Design | UMD | Course: Interaction Design | Grade: A+

Sep 2022 - Dec 2022

- Designed an app 'VRearth' using speculative design to demonstrate how apps might look in a given futuristic scenario
- Worked in a team of 4 and integrated our app prototypes to create a short film reflecting a persona's phone usage